（ゲロ寅）自来也は　わしに→
「ナルトへ蔵入りしろ」言うて死んだ。
Before he died,
Jiraiya said to me,
"go store yourself inside Naruto."
((何を言うなら！？
わしの腹には→
Are you crazy?!
ナルトの八卦封印に結合する鍵が
書き写されとるんじゃぞ。
The key that corresponds to
Naruto's Eight-Signed Seal
年々　四代目の封印も
弱まってきとる。
is transcribed on my belly!
Each year,
the Fourth Hokage's seal weakens!
いざというとき
それを締め直すために→
The key remains in order
to re-seal it
鍵が残されたんじゃ。
when it becomes necessary!
その大切な鍵を
金庫と一緒に置くなど→
To place such a key right next
to the safe is unheard of!
ありえんじゃろ。
（自来也）とはいえ
その鍵は　ミナトが残したもの。
Still, Minato entrusted it to us.
いずれは　ナルトに渡すべきだのう。
It was always meant to be
returned to Naruto.
まだ早い！　前に一度
お前にそそのかされて→
It's too soon!
Once you talked me into loosening
the Tetragram Seal…
鍵で四象封印を少し回しただけで
どうなったか→
You haven't forgotten
what the results were, have you?!
忘れたわけじゃなかろうが。
あぁ。
Yeah…
しかし　その鍵の術式を
ミナトがわしに預けたってことは→
However, the fact that Minato left me
the jutsu for the key
いずれは　あの術を
ナルトに完成させるのが→
convinces me that
he intended for Naruto
(あやつの意思だと　わしは思う))
to perfect that jutsu one day.
大じじ様　わしはホンマに
それで　ええんですかいのう？
Great Lord Elder!
Are you sure this is the right thing?
Jiraiya claimed that Naruto
could completely control
自来也は　ナルトなら→
九尾の力を完全に
コントロールできる言うて実験したが→
the power of the Nine-Tails,
but when we tested him,
it didn't go well.
うまくいかなかった。
But Jiraiya refused to give in,
ほいじゃけど自来也は
ミナトがそれを望んで→
saying that it was for that purpose
that Minato had sealed
九尾の半分をナルトに封印した言うて
きかんかった。
half of the Nine-Tails' chakra
inside of Naruto.
（フカサク）ハァ～。
Great Lord Elder, Gerotora himself
is the key to Naruto's Tetragram Seal.
大じじ様。
こやつは　ナルトの四象封印の鍵
そのものですじゃ。
Is it safe to hand him over to Naruto?
ナルトに渡しても
大丈夫じゃろうか？
What do you think?
どう思われます？
Have Naruto Uzumaki come here.
うずまきナルトを
ここへ呼ぶのじゃ。
I shall do a reading on him.
そやつの予言をわしが見る。
We will then see what
we must do.
事は　それからじゃ。
Huh? Is that true?
えっ　それは本当か？
It hasn't been officially
announced yet, but it's clear,
まだ正式には
発表されていないが→
judging from the activity in front of
the hut where she was resting.
お休みになられていた
小屋の騒ぎを見れば　一目瞭然だ。
It seems that all of her attendants,
who were all in such low spirits,
なんでも　あれだけ　ふさいでいた
お付きの人たちが→
have been gathering
there smiling!
みんな笑顔で
集まってきてるらしいわ。
I guess their prayers
have all been heard.
ようやく
皆の思いが通じたのかねぇ。
Please eat more slowly!
This is not enough!
（シズネ）ゆっくり食べてください。
My chakra hasn't returned
to normal!
（綱手）まだまだ足りん！
チャクラも元に戻ってない。
Bring me more food!
ハァ～。
If I'm not careful,
I'll become an old hag!
もっと食い物を持ってこい。
Uh-oh, no, no!
気を抜くと
ババアに戻っちまう。
The Hokage Quarters' supply stores
have run out.
やばい　やばい　やばい！
I'll go and requisition
more provisions,
火影室の食材は
もう底をつきました。
so please take a short break.
今から食材を
仕入れておきますので→
少し食休みをとられたら
いかがでしょうか？
No! Don't do it!
What are you thinking?!
（トントン）ブヒー！
This one is completely off limits!
ダ　ダメですよ！
何考えてるんですか？
What are you talking about?
Huh?
この子は絶対にダメ！
K-Kakashi…
ん？　何を言っている？
え？
I'm glad to see you so well.
カ…　カカシさん。
This is nothing,
I'm just getting started.
（カカシ）お元気そうで
よかったです。
After all you've eaten,
it doesn't make any sense.
まだまだだ。
朝飯前ってところだ。
I am relieved.
I was dangerously close
to becoming the Hokage.
こんだけ食べて
意味わかりませんよ。
ほっとしました。
But well, I'm not really
the Hokage type.
危うく俺が
火影になるところでしたよ。
Considering the present situation,
we need someone like you,
Lady Tsunade, with wide influence,
to be the Hokage.
まあ　俺は
火影ってガラじゃないし→
この状況下では
顔の利く綱手様が→
I must say I am amazed to hear
about the Allied Shinobi Force.
And I'm surprised that
火影でいてもらわないと。
the Tsuchikage and the Raikage
agreed to cooperate.
しかし　忍連合とは驚いたが→
That just goes to prove
what an awful situation
we are faced with.
よく土影や雷影が
協力する気になったもんだよ。
Madara Uchiha…
それだけ　まずい状況が
差し迫ってるってことです。
He's really still alive?
We don't have absolute proof,
うちはマダラ。
but considering what
they are trying to do,
本当に生きていたのか？
I'd say there's no doubt about it.
確証はありませんが→
Another war, huh?
やろうとしていることから
考えても→
Who would have thought
the karma of the Uchiha
would engulf all the shinobi
in the world.
まず間違いないかと。
また戦争か。
うちはの因果が　忍すべてを
巻き込むことになるとはな。
I will call a meeting immediately
after this meal!
We must prepare for war!
食後すぐに会議を開く。
戦争の準備だ。
（マダラ）当分は安静にしていろ。
万華鏡の場合は
なじむまで時間がかかる。
Prophecy of the Great Lord Elder
痛むか？
（サスケ）いや…。
You must rest for a while.
しっくりきている。
イタチの瞳力を感じる。
It takes some time to become
accustomed to the Mangekyo.
自分が
強くなっているのがわかる。
Are you in pain?
No.
It feels right. I can feel
Itachi's visual powers.
（香燐）でね　大蛇丸にずっと
過酷な労働を強いられて→
I can feel myself getting stronger!
そのあと
サスケがボスになったらなったで→
か弱い女の子の私に
ムチャな命令ばっかで。
INTEL DIVISION
And then, Orochimaru forced me
into hard labor.
最後は　ゴミのように…。
And when Sasuke took over
ウチだって被害者なの！
he kept giving poor old me
the most unreasonable demands.
そうか…　辛かったね。
In the end, he treated me like dirt.
（イビキ）ったく…。
I'm a victim too!
お前の生い立ちを
聞いてんじゃない。
I see. It must have been
hard on you!
暁　サスケ　カブトについての
情報を聞いている。
Jeez…
お前も　いちいち
感情移入するな！
We're not asking about
your personal history.
お前が落とされてどうする！
We are asking for intel on
the Akatsuki, Sasuke, and Kabuto.
す　すみません。
チェッ…　いいけど。
And don't get emotionally involved!
条件があるぜ　こっちとしても。
What good will it do if
you get swayed?
条件だと？
F-Forgive me.
まず一つ目。
ウチ　腹減ってる。
All right. But only if you
accept my conditions.
取り調べといったら
かつ丼だろ　こらっ！
Conditions?!
何が　かつ丼だ！
First of all… I'm starving!
里に　とんかつ屋なんて
なかったんじゃないかな？
If you interrogate someone,
あったとしても
この里の状況じゃ→
you're supposed to give 'em
a fried pork cutlet bowl, right?!
What do you mean
"a fried pork cutlet bowl"?!
営業なんてしてないだろ？
I didn't think there was
a fried pork cutlet bowl shop in the village.
一楽は仮店舗を建てて→
営業を再開したって
聞きましたけど。
Even if there were,
would it still be in business under
these circumstances?
うん…　ラーメンじゃダメか？
（香燐）ありえない！
ぜってぇ　かつ丼！
I heard that Ichiraku has started up
again in temporary quarters.
それじゃ　里以外から出前できるか
聞いてみるか。
Would ramen do?
No way. It has to be
a fried pork cutlet bowl.
かつ丼って
普通　そば屋にもありますよね。
Then, shall we see if
we can get delivery
う～ん　２日はかかるな。
from outside the village?
ったく　揃いも揃って！
す　すみません。
You can get a fried pork cutlet bowl
from a noodle shop too, can't you?
It would take about two days.
Cripes! What a pair!
《香燐：同じだ。
– F-Forgive me.
何なんだよ　この里も明るくて
あったかくて→
They're alike.
What is this?
アイツと同じだ…》
This village is cheerful…
and warm.
おお　ナルト
しばらく見かけなかったな。
Just like him.
どこ行ってたんだ？
（ナルト）ああ　いろいろ　その…。
Hey, Naruto!
Haven't seen you for a while.
アンタがいないと
寂しいじゃないかい。
Where were you?
Well…umm…
You see…umm…
アンタの元気は　里を回復させる
スタミナ源なんだからね。
It gets lonely when
you're not around.
エヘヘヘヘ　どうも　どうも。
Your liveliness gives the whole village
the energy to recover.
いつでも　おもてなしするぞ。
まいったな。
Thank you, thank you.
（木ノ葉丸）見たぞ　コレ。
（ウドン）うん。
Oh, man…
あれは　どう見ても
天狗になってるぞ　コレ。
I saw that.
（モエギ）ずっと　ニヤけて　や～ね。
Yeah.
His head is getting big,
I tell you.
問題だ　コレ。
Just look at him smiling away.
It's unpleasant.
俺たち　マスコミは　とてつもない
モンスターを作っちまった。
– This is a problem.
– Thank you, thank you.
We, the mass media,
have created a terrible monster.
ここで　ナルト兄ちゃんの
伸びた鼻を折らないと→
里のためによくないぞ　コレ。
うん！
If we don't take Naruto down
a peg or two,
the village is going to suffer.
どこに行こうとしてるのかしら。
Yeah.
よからぬところに
決まってるんだな　コレ。
I wonder where he's trying to go.
Nowhere good, I'm sure.
よし　決定的瞬間を
激写するんだ　コレ。
I've got it! We'll focus in
on the decisive moment!
うん！
– Yeah!
待ってろよ　愛しのキミよ
会いたかったぜ！
Wait for me, my love!
I've been waiting to see you!
やっぱりだ　コレ。
ん？
I was right!
《またアイツらか。
俺が気づいてないとでも
思ってんのかよ》
It's them again. Do they think
I haven't noticed them?
《どこまでも
ついてきやがって》
They're following me everywhere.
ヘヘッ。
ナルトさん。
ん？
Naruto…
里の英雄　ナルトさんですね。
You're the village hero,
Naruto, aren't you?
え？　アハハ　いやぁ　英雄だなんて。
Huh?
No, I'm no hero.
ところで
どちらへ行かれますの？　コレ。
By the way,
where are you headed, ey?
「コレ」！？　お前　木ノ葉丸だな。
"Ey"?!
You're Konohamaru, aren't you?!
木ノ葉丸じゃないのだ　コレ！
ウソつけ　この！
I am not Konohamaru, ey!
Don't lie!
ったく　この野郎！
Why you—!
待つんだ　コレ！
What's the big idea?!
こうなったら　こっちだって。
In that case, I'll do this!
多重影分身の術！
Multi Shadow Clone Jutsu!
You can't get away, ey!
逃がさないんだな　コレ。
Harem Jutsu!
ハーレムの術！
えぇ！？
– What?!
I want a word
with the village hero, ey!
里の英雄として　ひと言だ　コレ。
We got a tip that
you have a sweetheart, ey!
誰かに告白されたという情報が
入ってるんですが　コレ。
– Cripes!
– Who is it, ey?
どなたなんですか？　コレ。
Aren't you going on
a date now, ey?
これから
デートじゃないんですか？　コレ。
待て！
ああ　もう！
（シカマル）ふぅ…。
The village hero, huh?
里の英雄ね。
だけど…。
But…
Where are you going, ey?!
どこに行くんですか　コレ！
（ヒナタ）あのとき　私が
ペインに殺されかけたとき→
That time, when Naruto stood up
to Pain in order to protect me…
九尾が　ナルト君の体に現れて…。
the Nine-Tails appeared in Naruto's body.
((サクラ：あれは…！
That's…
(（ペイン）俺が憎いか？))
Do you hate me?
I could feel its intense anger,
激しい怒りを感じた。
but I couldn't feel any
of Naruto's will.
でも　そこに　ナルト君の意思を
感じることができなかった。
It was like his anger had
taken over his heart.
まるで　怒りに
のっとられたみたいに…。
All because of that Nine-Tails.
心を…　あの九尾に…。
Now that the First Hokage's necklace
（ヤマト）綱手様からもらった
初代火影のペンダントを失った今→
that Naruto received
from Lady Tsunade is lost,
if the Nine-Tails should
ever run loose…
もし　九尾が暴走したら→
even I couldn't stop it.
僕でも止めることはできない。
True, it would be
tremendously risky
《確かに　九尾を抱えて
暁と戦うことには→
to take on the Akatsuki
with the Nine-Tails inside him.
とてつもない　リスクがある。
But…
だが…》
– O-Oh no!
– Wait up! Naruto, ey!
待つんだ　コレ！
He is Naruto.
《アイツは　ナルトだ。
九尾なんかじゃねえ。
He's not the Nine-Tails.
For this battle,
we don't need the Nine-Tails.
この戦いには　九尾じゃねえ
ナルトの力が必要だ。
We need Naruto's strength.
If it looks like the Nine-Tails
is going to take over,
we have to stop it.
九尾が　でしゃばるようなら→
That's right.
俺たちが　それを
止めるっきゃねえ。
This is also a battle in which
そうだ　これは　暁と九尾から
ナルトを守る戦いでもある。
we must protect Naruto from
the Akatsuki and the Nine-Tails.
That's how I…no…
I'm sure this is how
all of my classmates feel.
俺の…　いや　おそらくは
俺たち同期の考えは一緒だろう。
We will protect Naruto,
and we will fight with Naruto.
ナルトを守り　ナルトとともに戦う。
I wonder what Lady Tsunade thinks.
綱手様は　どう思っている？》
みんな揃ったな。
これより　戦争に向けた
作戦会議を始める。
Is everyone here?
We shall now start our war council
to discuss strategy!
（コハル）まず忍具
食糧の備蓄を始めよ。
First, assemble reserves of
ninja tools and foodstuffs.
忍を戦闘部隊と
支援部隊に二分割し→
We must divide our shinobi into
main battle units and support forces,
戦闘部隊の小隊の組み方を
検討しろ。
and consider how we should
build the platoons
within the fighting forces!
すべての忍のリストを　ここへ。
Bring me the complete list
of all our shinobi!
戦争かぁ…
いよいよ動き出したな。
So it's war.
So it's finally come to that.
（シカク）作戦会議に呼ばれたとはいえ
お前は　まだ若い。
You were invited to this war council,
but you're still young.
よく聞いて　抜かりなくな。
Keep your ears open
and don't miss a thing.
ああ　んなこたぁ
わかってるって。
Yeah. I know that.
頭フルに使って
すべて　たたきこむ。
I will make full use of my head
and hammer everything in!
はぁ　ようやくまいたか。
I guess I finally lost them.
これで　心置きなく
愛しのキミを堪能できるってばよ！
Now, finally, I can enjoy
my love to the fullest!
おっちゃん
味噌とんこつチャーシュー　大盛り！
Old man! One large tonkotsu miso
with BBQ pork!
（サクラ）ナルト！
Naruto!
Huh?!
え？　じゃあ
綱手のばあちゃん→
So Grandma Tsunade is fine now?
もう　大丈夫なんだな？
Yes!
うん！
よっしゃ！
All right!
Is that right?
I'm happy about Lady Tsunade.
（テウチ）そうか　よかったな　綱手様。
Okay! Since this is good news,
the ramen is on me!
よし　めでてえから
ラーメンはおごりだ！
Huh?! Are you sure?!
えっ　いいの？
Why don't you have some too, Sakura?
サクラも一緒にどうだ？
ああ　ううん。
No thanks.
I still have more people to notify.
まだ他にも知らせに回らないと
いけないから。
Well, I'll see you later, Naruto!
じゃあ　あとでね　ナルト。
ハハッ！
Now that that's off my mind,
I feel hungrier than ever!
安心したら　ますます
腹減ってきたってばよ。
Okay! I'm eating my fill today.
よし！　今日は食うぞ！
１杯　２杯　３杯と！
One bowl, two bowls, three bowls!
Here you go!
へい　お待ち　火影様回復記念
特製とんこつ味噌チャーシューだ。
It's a special tonkotsu miso
with BBQ pork slices
to celebrate the Hokage's recovery!
Whoa!
ウハッ！
Thank you for the…
いただき…。
Oh? He disappeared.
ありゃ　消えた。
…food!
ま～す！
いきなり飯に
がっつくとはのう。
I'm surprised he dug right
into the food.
（シマ）よっぽど　私のムシ料理が
気に入ってくれとったんじゃねえ。
Looks like he really loves
my bug cooking!
おえ～！
What am I doing here again?
なんでまた　ここに？
ワシが逆口寄せしたんじゃ。
I did a Reverse Summoning on you.
The Great Lord Elder will
divine your future, Naruto-boy.
ナルトちゃんにも
これから大じじ様の予言が出る。
予言？
Divine?
Follow me.
ワシについて来るんじゃ。
おえ～！
Don't throw it up!
（シマ）吐くなや～！
連れて来ました。
オッス！
久しぶりだってばよ！
デカじいちゃん仙人！
I have brought him.
ほほ～　呼んだのは他でもない。
Hey! Long time no see,
Giant Gramps Sage!
え～と　え～…。
It was indeed I who
summoned you…er…umm…
誰じゃったかいのお？
うずまきナルト。
Who're you again?
もういいかげん
名前覚えてくれって。
Naruto Uzumaki!
デカじいちゃん仙人ってばよ。
I wish you'd hurry up and
learn my name, Giant Gramps Sage!
ああ～　そうじゃった
そうじゃった。
ナルトじゃあ。
Oh, that's right, that's right.
It's Naruto.
《はあ　毎回このくだりを
やらんといけんのかいな》
ナルトよ　お前への予言を見た。
Do we have to go through
this every time?
Listen, Naruto.
予言か…　いいぜ　覚悟はできてる。
I have seen
a prophecy involving you.
A prophecy?
Okay, I'm ready for it.
ならば　心して聞け。
In that case, listen carefully.
お前は　これから　タコに会う。
You will soon be meeting
an octopus.
え？
タコ？
An octopus?
なんで　タコなんかと？
さぁ　のう？
Why an octopus?
わしも　はっきりとは見えぬが
タコの足に違いない。
Well, I couldn't see too clearly,
but I'm sure
they were octopus arms.
それから　お前は→
And then, it will come to pass that
眼に力を宿している少年と
戦うことになる。
you will fight a young ma
そして…。
ああ　わかってる。
わかっておるとは
どういうことじゃ？
((俺は　変わりはしねえ！
お前と　わかりあう気もねえ！
死ぬ気もねえ！
死ぬのは　お前だ！
死ぬなら一緒だ　サスケ。
フンッ！
いいだろう！　お前を
いちばんに殺してやる！
俺ってば　まだ　お前に　ちゃんと
認めてもらってねえからよ。
もういい　ナルト！
サスケは俺がやる！
お前には　火影になるって
大切な夢がある。
サスケの道連れで
お前が潰れることは…。
仲間一人救えねえヤツが
火影になんて　なれるかよ！
(サスケとは　俺がやる！))
おぬし　見えたのか？
ああ！
あの眼に力を宿した少年→
あやつが
何者であるか　わかったと？
うん！　全部　覚悟してる。
ゲロ寅よ！
ナルトへ蔵入りする予言も見た。
な　なんですと！？
四代目の封印を渡してやれ。
う～ん…　大じじ様が言うなら
しゃあないわい！
これって…。
四代目火影が残した→
お前の腹の封印術を
開け閉めする鍵じゃ！
これで　やろうと思えば→
九尾を野放しにだってできる。
そこの四角のところに
手を押せ。
これは　自来也の言っとった
あの術を完成させる手段を→
手に入れたことにもなるんじゃ。
九尾の封印を解く鍵…。
迷っているのか？　ナルト。
＜デンマークからの贈り物。　レゴブロック
レゴブロック同士を
組み合わせるだけで→
どんな形にも生まれ変わる
変幻自在の夢のおもちゃ。
豊かな発想が　クオリティを高め→
進化した作品が更なる発想を生む。
そんなレゴブロックを極めた達人が
ここに集結＞